让我们再看看我们在一两代之前引入的平均过程。这里
Let’s look again at the averaging process that we introduced a segment or two ago. Here
我们有蒙娜丽莎的原始形象，在这里我们有蒙娜丽莎的版本
we have our original image of the Mona Lisa and here we have the version of the Mona Lisa
我们在21x21像素输入窗口上应用了平均值。会发生什么
where we have applied an averaging over a 21 by 21 pixel input window. What can happen
当我们在一个方形窗口上执行平均值时，它会导致图像中的人工制品
when we perform the average over a square window it leads to an artefact in the image
叫响了。它引入了非常微弱的垂直和水平线，我们可以看到一些
called ringing. It introduces very faint vertical and horizontal lines and we can see a few
在她的嘴唇之上，在她的眼睛上方和下方。出现这个问题是因为像素中的
above her lips and above and below her eyes. This problem arises because the pixels in
输入窗口距离窗口中心的距离不同。特别是，
the input window are different distances away from the centre of the window. In particular,
这里的这个像素是距离窗口中心2个距离的距离
this pixel here is the distance of 2 away from the centre of the window where this pixel
这里距离市中心2√2。这是一个差不多3个像素的值
here is a distance 2√2 away from the centre. That is a value of almost 3 pixels away from
中心。结果是平均值受像素值的不当影响
the centre. And the result is that the average is unduly influenced by pixel values that
距离市中心很远。我们说这个操作不是各向同性的;那
are a long way from the centre. And we say that this operation is not isotropic; that
意味着它在不同方向上有不同的结果。它不是对称的。
means that it has different results in different directions. It is not symmetrical.
理想情况下，我们想要做的是提取像素的圆形区域;我们想
Ideally what we would like to do is to extract a circular region of pixels; we would like
获取落在此圆盘下方的所有像素。但问题是这个
to take all of the pixels that fall underneath this circular disk. But the problem with this
是磁盘没有完全覆盖所有像素;周围的一些像素
is that the disk doesn’t fully cover all of the pixels; some of the pixels around the
边缘-尤其是角落中的边缘-仅被磁盘部分覆盖。以便
edge — particularly the ones in the corner — are only partially covered by the disk. So that
让我们拍摄一小部分像素。让我们来看看我们可以做到这一点的方式。
involves us taking a fraction of a pixel. Let’s look at a way we can do this.
我们这样做的方式是应用加权。让我们放大这个圆形区域
And the way we do it is to apply a weighting. Let’s zoom in on this circular region that
我们创建了它，它是一个直径为2.5像素的圆。我们想要
we have created and it’s a circle with a diameter of 2.5 pixels. And we want to take
所有这些像素，因为它完全被磁盘覆盖。但我们只想采取一小部分
all of this pixel because it is fully covered by the disk. But we only want to take a fraction
这个像素;我们希望它在平均值上具有较小的重要性或较小的权重
of this pixel; we want it to have less significance or less weight in the average that we are
去计算。所以我们能做的就是计算一组权重。
going to compute. So what we can do is to compute a set of weights.
对于完全被磁盘覆盖的像素，权重等于1.但是如果是磁盘
For pixels that are fully covered by the disk, the weight is equal to 1. But if the disk
只有部分覆盖像素，然后重量小于一，我们可以看到那里
only partly covers the pixel then the weight is less than one and we can see that there
有些像素被磁盘覆盖了98％，在角落里我们可以看到一些像素
are some pixels 98% covered by the disk and in the corners we can see that some pixels
只有14％的磁盘覆盖。然后该矩阵表示不同的影响
are only 14% covered by the disk. This matrix then represents the influence that the different
方形窗口内的像素应该具有得到的平均值。我们如何使用它
pixels within the square window should have on the resulting average. How do we use this
加权矩阵？我们要做的就是全力以赴
weighting matrix? What we are going to do is to take all of
来自输入图像的像素，这里是一组像素值的示例。和我们
the pixels from the input image and here is an example of a set of pixel values. And we
将通过加权矩阵将窗口内的所有像素相乘。还有这个
are going to multiply all of the pixels within the window by the weighting matrix. And this
是元素明智的乘法，有时称为希尔伯特乘法。所以我们采取
is an element wise multiplication, sometimes called a Hilbert multiplication. So we take
来自这两个矩阵的相应元素，将它们相乘，将结果放入
corresponding elements from these two matrices, multiply them together, put the result into
输出矩阵中的对应元素。所以在这里我们有像素值
the corresponding element in the output matrix. So over here we have the pixel value from
原始图像，但我们用加权矩阵乘以它们
the original image, but we have multiplied them by the weighting matrix so that the ones
在角落里有一个较低的价值，不太能够影响平均值。现在
in the corners have got a lower value, less able to influence the resulting average. Now
我们将计算该产品的总和，这是所有像素的乘积
we will compute the sum over this product and that is the product of all of the pixels
在输入窗口中，我们用W和加权矩阵中的所有值表示。
in the input window which we denote by W and all of the values in the weighting matrix.
我现在要将加权矩阵称为内核。
And I am going to now refer to that weighting matrix as a kernel.
内核是一种常用于图像处理的术语。我们要计算
Kernel is a term that is commonly used in image processing. And we are going to compute
这两个小方形图像的元素乘法和结果的总和
the sum of the element wise multiplication of these two small square images and the result
是我们放入输出图像的东西。所以我们的函数f（W）等于
is what we place into the output image. So our function f(W) is equal to the sum of the
元素明智地乘以输入窗口和内核。
element wise multiplication of the input window and the kernel.
现在考虑我有一个输入图像，其中所有像素均匀且等于
Consider now that I have an input image where all of the pixels are uniform and equal to
1.如果我将此内核应用于该图像，结果将是该图像中的每个像素
1. If I applied this kernel to that image, the result will be that every pixel in the
输出图像的值为19.6。输入图像，值均为1，输出图像
output image would have a value of 19.6. Input image, the values are all 1, output image
都是19.6。我们可以通过应用比例因子和比例因子来解决这个问题
are all 19.6. And we can get around this by applying a scale factor, and a scale factor
由内核中所有元素的总和确定;如果我们划分内核
is determined from the sum of all of the elements within the kernel; if we divide the kernel
通过它的所有元素的总和，我们有一个规范化的内核，如果我们应用它
by the sum of all of its elements we have a normalised kernel and if we apply this to
一个图像，其中所有输入像素的值都为1，输出图像将具有
an image, where all of the input pixels have got a value of 1, the output image will have
它的所有像素都等于1。这是一个规范化的内核，所以通常我们尝试和
all of its pixels equal to one. This is a normalised kernel, so typically we try and
计算一个比例因子为1的内核。
compute a kernel that has got a scale factor of 1.
所以我们在本讲座开头就看到了简单的平均值
So the simple averaging that we looked at right at the beginning of this lecture we
也可以把它想象成一个内核。事实上，它是一个非常简单的内核所有的
can also think of it as a kernel. In fact, it is a very simple kernel where all of the
窗口中的元素等于1.所以这是7乘7窗口的示例。该
elements in the window are equal to 1. So here is the example for a 7 by 7 window. The
我们将7乘7的矩阵除以49，使整体比例因子相等
7 by 7 matrix of ones, we divide it by 49 so that the overall scale factor is equal
因此，这是处理空间操作的一种相当统一的方式-它们都可以
to 1. So this is a fairly uniform way of dealing with spatial operations—they can all be
由内核矩阵表示。在MATLAB工具箱中，我们使用一个名为iconv的函数。
represented by a kernel matrix. And in the MATLAB tool box we use a function called iconv.
我们传递了图像，在这种情况下传递了蒙娜丽莎图像。第二个论点是
We pass in the image and in this case the Mona Lisa image. The second argument is the
在这种情况下，核矩阵是一个7乘7的矩阵，其中有一个除以49.该函数
kernel matrix in this case it is a 7 by 7 matrix full of ones, divided by 49. The function
ones是内置的MATLAB函数。另一个在图像中常用的内核
ones is a built-in MATLAB function. Another kernel that is commonly used in image
处理是高斯核心，以着名的德国数学家卡尔-弗里德里希命名
processing is the Gaussian kernel, named after the very famous German mathematician Carl-Friedrich
高斯。您之前可能遇到过此函数的一维版本;
Gauss. You have perhaps encountered the one dimensional version of this function before;
这是我们在统计中看到的正态分布。这个功能很简单
it is the normal distribution that we see in statistics. This function has got a simple
优雅的分析形式，如果我们在三维中绘制它有外观
and elegant analytic form and if we plot it in three dimensions it has the appearance
一个平缓的山丘。相反，如果我们将此功能表示为亮度的图像
of a gentle hill. If, instead, we represent this function as an image where brightness
与左侧显示的函数的高度成正比，我们有一个图像
is proportional to height of the function shown over on the left, we have an image that
看起来像这样。中间是明亮的，我们可以看到强度
looks something like this. It is bright in the middle and we can see that the intensity
在所有方向均匀地脱落。这是各向同性的功能，重量减少
falls off uniformly in all directions. This is an isotropic function and the weight decreases
当我们离开中心时。在MATLAB工具箱中，我们可以使用计算这个内核
as we move away from the centre. In the MATLAB tool box, we can compute this kernel using
功能kgauss。第一个参数是标准差，即符号σ
the function kgauss. The first argument is the standard deviation, the symbol σ on the
left，第二个参数是内核的半宽。在这种情况下，一半
left, and the second argument is the half width of the kernel. In this case, the half
宽度为15因此全宽为2x15+1;也就是说，一个31的内核
width is 15 so therefore the full width is 2x15 + 1; that is, a kernel that is 31 by
31像素。内核的一个重要参数是
31 pixels. An important parameter of the kernel is the
标准偏差，符号σ，在分析表达式中出现两次。它控制着
standard deviation, the symbol σ, which appears twice in the analytic expression. It controls
内核的宽度，因此对于σ为2，我们看到有一个非常高的尖峰;
the width of the kernels, so for a σ of 2 we see that there is a very tall, pointy peak;
对于σ为5，它更广泛;对于σ10，它仍然更广泛。高斯下的区域
for a σ of 5 it is much broader; for σ 10 it is broader still. The area under the Gaussian
功能总是一个。随着它越来越宽，它变得不那么高了。重要的考虑因素
function is always one. So as it gets wider it becomes less tall. An important consideration
当我们使用高斯进行图像处理时，内核应该是多大的。内核
when we use the Gaussian for image processing is what size should the kernel be. The kernel
需要足够大才能保持高斯的大部分，这显然正在发生
needs to be big enough to hold the bulk of the Gaussian so, and that clearly is going
取决于标准偏差。因此，一个非常好的经验法则是制作一半
to depend on the standard deviation. So a pretty good rule of thumb is to make the half
内核的宽度等于标准偏差的三倍。
width of the kernel equal to three times the standard deviation.
让我们创建其中一个高斯内核;我将把它放入一个名为的变量中
Let’s create one of these Gaussian kernels; I am going to put it into a variable called
K.这是kgauss函数，我希望它的标准偏差为5，我想要
K. It is the kgauss function and I want it to have a standard deviation of 5 and I wanted
在一个半宽为15的窗口中。所以这实际上是31个31内核。
to be in a window with a half width of 15. So that will actually be 31 by 31 kernel.
我们走了。我们在工作空间中创建了一个31乘31的矩阵，其中包含高斯核。
There we go. We have created a 31 by 31 matrix in the workspace which contains the Gaussian kernel.
现在我可以将其显示为图像。
Now I can display this as an image.
在那里我们看到它本质上是一个磁盘，
And there we see it is essentially a disk,
它在中间是明亮的，它对窗口中心的值有很高的权重
it is bright in the middle, it has got a high weighting to values in the centre of the window
并且对于远离窗口中心的像素的权重较低。
and lower weighting for pixels that are further away from the centre of the window.
现在我可以创建一个新的数字。我可以用不同的方式看待它;我可以看看
Now I can create in a new figure. And I can look at it in a different way; I can look
通过创建MATLAB曲面图以三维方式实现它。在那里我们看到了
at it in a three dimensional way by creating a MATLAB surface plot. And there we see the
高斯窗口，形状非常鲜明。中间高，价值下降
Gaussian window, very distinctive shape. Tall in the middle and with the decreasing values
因为我们离开中心。让我们将此内核应用于标准测试图像，
as we go away from the centre. Let’s apply this kernel to a standard test image,
所以我们将加载蒙娜丽莎的图像。
so we will load the Mona Lisa image.
我将创建一个名为S的新图像用于平滑，我将它与内核相关联。
I will create a new image called S for smooth and I will correlate it with the kernel.
我们在那里创建了输出图像。我可以显示
There we have created the output image. I can display
那我们可以看到图像已经过平滑处理;我们也可能会说它看起来有点像
that and we can see that the image has been smoothed; we might also say it looks a bit
模糊。看起来它失去了一些解决方案。我们所做的就是顺利完成
blurry. Looks like it has lost some of its resolution. What we’ve done is smooth out
非常精细的比例细节，只留下图像中的粗细节。
the very fine scale detail and left just the coarse detail in the image.
你可以看到，对于Kσ等于2，我们有一个相对较小的内核大小;对于
And you can see that for the Kσ equals 2, we have a relatively small kernel size; for
σ等于5，我们必须使用更大的内核。
σ equals 5, we have to use a much larger kernel.